Now that you've run your first program,
이제 첫 프로그램을
I'd like to share with you some tips
실행하셨으니,
for learning to code.
코딩을 배우기 위한
First is, do try the code.
몇 가지 팁을
Do pause the videos and do run the code.
공유해 드리고자 합니다.
To test your understanding of how line of code works,
첫 번째는 코드를 직접 해보는 겁니다.
try asking yourself questions like,
동영상을 멈추고
what do I think will happen if I leave
직접 코드를 실행해 보세요.
a quotation mark out or if I
코드 한 줄이 어떻게 작동하는지
accidentally have two instead of
이해도를 확인하려면,
one closing parentheses and then change the code,
닫는 괄호 하나를 넣고 코드를 변경한 다음,
run it and see if you are right.
실행해서 맞는지 확인해 보세요.
To give yourself practice,
연습을 위해,
I also encourage you to complete the practice exercises.
연습 문제도 꼭 풀어보시길 권합니다.
I also encourage you to use
챗봇을 활용하는 것도
a chatbot as often as you want.
원하는 만큼 자주 해보시길 권합니다.
Think of the AI chatbot as your buddy or
AI 챗봇을 여러분의 친구나
your coding companion who knows
파이썬을 아주 잘 알고
Python pretty well and is patient,
인내심도 있으며 그저
and just wants to help you out.
여러분을 돕고 싶어 하는 코딩 동료라고 생각하세요.
While going through this course,
이 과정을 진행하면서,
you might think of some what if or why questions.
몇 가지 '만약 ~라면' 또는
What if I did that? Why is it like that?
'왜'라는 질문이 떠오를 수도 있습니다.
Go ahead and ask the chatbot
제가 그렇게 했다면요?
as many questions as you want.
그건 왜 그런 거죠?
You can also ask your chatbot to explain
챗봇에게 마음껏 물어보세요.
codes and sometimes ask you, how does this code work?
원하는 만큼 얼마든지요.
What is it doing that might help you
또한 챗봇에게 요청하여
understand what a piece of code is actually doing?
코드를 설명해 달라고 하거나,
This is actually what professional
가끔은 질문을 던지게 할 수도 있습니다.
software developers do today as well.
소프트웨어 개발자들도
When there's a piece of code, I don't understand.
오늘날에도 마찬가지입니다.
I will paste it into
이해하기 어려운
chatbot sometimes and see if it can help me out.
코드가 있을 때는요.
When you're coding and running code is totally
챗봇에 붙여넣어서
fine if something doesn't work the first time round,
가끔 도움이 되는지
[inaudible] code are completely expected.
확인하기도 합니다.
After all, this may be a brand new language for you,
코딩을 하고 코드를
and as when you're learning to
실행할 때, 처음부터 잘
speak Spanish or French for the first time,
안 되더라도 전혀
you won't say everything right the first time round.
모든 걸 다
We should expect to say when you're
한 번에 맞추진 못할 겁니다.
learning a new programming language.
우리는
You won't get everything right the first time round.
새로운
If it doesn't work the first time
프로그래밍 언어를
around, that's totally fine.
배울 때를 예상해야 합니다.
Just try a different approach if you can think of
모든 것을 다
one or ask the chatbot for help.
한 번에 맞추진 못할 겁니다.
In fact, the chatbot can also help
만약 잘
you read and understand error messages.
되지 않더라도
Finally, instead of just copy pasting answers
마지막으로, 단순히
from the chatbot into your code,
챗봇 답변을 복사 붙여넣기만
consider also reading the chatbot's response to
코드에 하는 것에서 벗어나,
see if the chatbot can share of your new perspective,
챗봇의 답변을
or teach you something rather
읽어보는 것도 고려해 보세요.
than just give you the answer.
챗봇이 당신의
That way hopefully, you also keep on
새로운 관점을 공유하거나,
deepening your understanding of coding.
단순히 답을 주는 것보다
I hope you feel free to learn at your own pace.
무언가를 가르쳐줄 수 있을지 살펴보세요.
Pause the videos what you want.
그렇게 하면 바라건대,
When I'm learning online,
온라인으로 배울 때,
I often pause the video when
저는 비디오를 자주 멈춥니다.
I feel like I need to think and then
생각할 시간이 필요하다고 느낄 때요. 그리고 나서
come back only when I
다시 돌아오는 건 제가
feel like I've gotten one to move on,
다음으로 넘어갈 준비가 됐다고 느껴질 때뿐이죠.
and feel free to go as fast or as slow as
그리고 원하는 만큼 빠르거나 느리게 진행하세요.
you want to make sure
이 개념들을 확실히 이해했는지
you're understanding these concepts.
확인하기 위해서요.
Learning to code is really fun,
코딩을 배우는 건 정말 재밌어요.
and I hope these tips make
그리고 이 팁들이 도움이 되기를 바라요.
this even more enjoyable for you.
이것을 훨씬 더
With that, let's go on to
즐겁게 해드릴 거예요.
the next video on data in Python.
그럼 다음으로